Guide to the Samuel Weinbaum papers 2019.012
Brooklyn Historical Society
Samuel Weinbaum papers
1967-1988
1954-1993
Brooklyn Historical Society
Weinbaum, Samuel
2019.012
4.5 Linear Feet in 9 manuscript boxes and 1 16x20 folder.
The Samuel Weinbaum papers consists of legal documents created and collected by Samuel Weinbaum over the course of his work as a lawyer who primarily represented the Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America, Local 12 and 39 (AFL-CIO). The material in the collection dates from 1963 to 1993 with the bulk of the papers spanning 1967 to 1988. The bulk of the collection documents union negotiations with Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation and Todd Shipyards Corporation. The collection also includes a small amount of grievance and arbitration documents between United Service Workers of America, Amalgamated Local Union 355 and D & W Central Station Alarm Company.
Content Description
Samuel Weinbaum (b. 1929) is a lawyer who represented the Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America Locals 12 and 39 (AFL-CIO), both of which are now defunct. The locals represented workers at Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, in the Brooklyn Navy Yard, and the Todd Shipyard in Red Hook from the late 1960s through the closure of the shipyards in the 1980s.
Appraisal
During processing, folders of invoices, medical reports, and cancelled checks were deaccessioned from the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions with the exception of materials in box 9 which are restricted until 2096.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gifted to Brooklyn Historical Society by Samuel Weinbaum on November 8, 2019.
Scope and Contents
The Samuel Weinbaum papers consists of legal documents created and collected by Samuel Weinbaum dating from 1963 to 1993 pertaining to his work as a lawyer representing Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America Locals 12 and 39 (AFL-CIO) and United Service Workers of America, Amalgamated Local Union 355. The bulk of the collection contains grievance and arbitration files from Weinbaum's work representing Local 12 and 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. during union negotiations with Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, Todd Shipyards Corporation, and Reynolds Shipyard Corporation. Other documents in the collection pertains to Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A.'s negotiations with Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation during their bankruptcy proceedings in 1986. Material from these events include: legal filings, research notes, labor agreement drafts, labor agreements, union membership forms, grievance claim forms, legal pamphlets, and correspondence.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into three series. The arrangement of the collection groups material by subject matter. The arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Grievance and Arbitration Files, 1962-1993, undated Series II. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation Bankruptcy Records, 1985-1988 Series III. Labor Negotiations and Agreements, 1954-1991, undated
Navy-yards and naval stations -- New York (State) -- Kings County -- Employees; Red Hook (New York, N.Y.); New York Naval Shipyard; Ships -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Legal documents; Shipbuilding industry -- Employees -- Labor unions; Court records -- New York (State); Law offices -- Records and correspondence; Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America; Todd Shipyards Corporation. Brooklyn Division; Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation; Reynolds Shipyard Corporation
- Series I. Grievance and Arbitration Files, 1962-1993, undated; 2.5 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes.
  Arrangement
  Documents in this series are grouped alphabetically by corporation name, then arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains correspondence, legal notices, orders, awards, petitions, affidavits, opinions, notes and research, case files, grievance forms, and transcripts documenting the cases when Samuel Weinbaum represented Local 12 and 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. and Local 355, U.S.W.A. Included in this series is a folder of material from Samuel Weinbaum's work as an arbitrator.
  - Correspondence -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation v. Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notes -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation v. Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation v. Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Notes and Decisions -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation v. Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1980-1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Material in this folder is restricted until 2096.
  - Correspondence -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation v. Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Notices, and Orders -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation v. Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Petitions, and Affidavit -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation v. Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Memorandum and Notice -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation v. Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notices, Correspondence, and Orders -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9, Folder 10)
  - Notices, Petitions, and Judgments -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Filings -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Notes and Correspondence -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation v. Torrente and Hinds, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Notes and Statements -- Robert Torrente Investigation at Coast Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Reports and Correspondence -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Notes -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Complaint, Summons, Affidavit, Demands, and Correspondence -- Jorge Contreras v. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation and Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- D & W Central Station Alarm Company v. Local 355, U.S.W.A., 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Opinions, Award, and Charge -- Sangala Chambo v. D & W Central Station Alarm Company, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence -- Amalgamated Local Union 355 v. D & W Central Station Alarm Company, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Log, Reports, and Stipulations -- Julia Silverman v. Madison Square Garden, Inc. et al, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Award, Opinions, and Notes -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Reynolds Shipyard Corporation, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12, Folder 13)
  - Case Files -- Todd Shipyards Corporation v. Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Grievance Forms -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1962-1978; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notes and Research -- Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1964-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Award -- Todd Shipyards Corporation v. Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1966-1968, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 15 and Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, August 2, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Opinions -- Todd Shipyards Corporation. v. Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notices and Correspondence -- Todd Shipyards Corporation v. Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Notices and Correspondence -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, March 24, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Notices and Correspondence -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notices and Correspondence -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Notices, and Complaints -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards, Inc., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notices and Correspondence -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, May 23, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Notices and Correspondence -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, March 13, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, March 20, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, May 10, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, September 14, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, November 30, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, November 12, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, March 24, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, April 9, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, October 20, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hearing Transcripts -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, October 28, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, November 4, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Notices and Correspondence -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Case Files -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, February 5, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Hearing Transcripts -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, May 2 and 19, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hearing Transcripts -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, September 23, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hearing Transcripts -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, January 17, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, February 4, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Hearing Transcript -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, February 25, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Notices and Correspondence -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Case Files -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A. v. Todd Shipyards Corporation, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence and Filings -- Todd Shipyards Corporation v. Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence -- Todd Shipyard Corporation v. Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Summons and Complaint -- Alice Simmons et al v. Pablo C. Negron et al, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Notes, and Awards -- Multiple Cases, 1980-1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Awards, and Opinions -- Samuel Weinbaum, Arbitrator, 1977-1981 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Appeals Briefs, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Labor Relations Board Notices and Decisions, circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Grievances, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Notes on Grievances and Arbitration, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Notes on Arbitration, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notes on Grievances and Arbitration, 1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Series II. Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation Bankruptcy Records, 1985-1988; .5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box.
  This series is grouped alphabetically by document type, then arranged chronologically.
  This small series contains orders, notices, press clippings, research notes, correspondence, petitions, and records pertaining to Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A.'s negotiations with Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation during their bankruptcy proceedings in 1986.
  - Bankruptcy Notes and Research, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Bankruptcy Petition, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. Membership Not Eligible for Early Retirement Records, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Notice -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation Chapter 11 Case, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Notices and Motions, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Orders and Notices, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6 - 10)
  - Orders and Notices, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 11 - 13)
  - Press Clippings, 1985-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Publications Relating to Labor Law and Bankruptcy, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Series III. Labor Negotiations and Agreements, 1954-1991, undated; 1.5 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 1 16x20 folder.
  This series contains correspondence, agreement drafts, bylaws, final agreements, pamphlets, applications, and research notes that pertain to Local 12 and 39, I.U.M.S.W.A.'s labor negotiations and agreements with Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation and Todd Shipyards Corporation. There is also a small amount of material in this series from Local 838, Lathe Hoisters' Union.
  - Benefits Pamphlets -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation and Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- Todd Shipyards Corporation and Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1974 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Draft Agreements -- Local 355, United Service Workers of America, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Labor Agreement and Bylaws -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Labor Agreement Draft -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation and Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - IRS Annual Return/Report of Employee Benefit Plan Form -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - I.U.M.S.W.A. Constitution and Bylaws, 1954-1984 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - I.U.M.S.W.A. Purchase of 267 52nd Street, Brooklyn, NY, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Labor Agreement Draft -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation and Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Labor Agreement Pamphlet -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1963-1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Labor Agreements Pamphlet -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1966, 1972, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Labor Agreement Pamphlet -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A and Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Labor Agreements Pamphlet -- Local 12 and Local 13, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1975, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Labor Agreement Proposals -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation and Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Lathe Hoisters' Union, Local 838, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Membership -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Member Compensation and Benefits -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Member Compensation and Benefits, A-D -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Member Compensation and Benefits, E-J -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Member Compensation and Benefits, K-Z -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Member Vacation Request Applications -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Negotiation Notes, Local 838, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Notes and Correspondence -- Sub-Contracting Local 13, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1980-1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Notes and Drafts -- Contract Negotiations, 1984, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Notes and Research, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Page Proofs -- Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation and Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlet -- "A layman's guide to basic law under the National Labor Relations Act", 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Pension Plan Pamphlet -- Local 39, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Preliminary Agreement -- Local 6, I.U.M.S.W.A., 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Research, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Supplemental Agreement -- Local 12, I.U.M.S.W.A. and Coastal Dry Dock and Repair Corporation, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Two Photographs, undated (Box OS-38, Folder 11)